Finding Aid for Isaac Newton Elwood papers, 1866-1885
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Isaac Newton Elwood papers 1866-1885
Elwood, Isaac Newton, 1843-1887.
2.5 linear feet
851258 Aa 2
Methodist Episcopal clergyman; sermons.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Alice M. Elwood (donor no. 835 ) in 1939.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Isaac Newton Elwood was born in Starkville, Herkimer County, New York, May 11, 1843. He graduated from the University of Michigan in 1867. Soon thereafter, he was admitted on trial to the Detroit Annual Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church. His ministerial appointments were: Marquette, 1867-1868; Fenton, 1869; Saginaw, 1870-1871; Morenci, 1872-1874; Ann Arbor, 1875; Port Huron, 1876; Port Huron District, 1877-1880; Ypsilanti, 1881-1883, and Court Street in Flint, 1884-1885. He died in Flint, January 19, 1887.
The Elwood collection consists of sermons and outlines and notes for sermons delivered in Marquette, Fenton, Saginaw, Morenci, Ann Arbor, Port Huron, Ypsilanti, and Flint, Michigan. Also included are sermons on temperance, an essay on Charles Sumner (1866), and a brief history of Sunday School in Morenci, Michigan.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Clergy--Michigan; Fenton (Mich.); Marquette (Mich.); Methodist Episcopal Church--Michigan; Morenci (Mich.); Port Huron (Mich.); Sunday schools--Michigan--Morenci; Saginaw (Mich.); Sumner, Charles, 1811-1874; Temperance--Michigan; Ypsilanti (Mich.)
Genre Terms:
Sermons.
- Sermons
  - Marquette, 1867-1869, 12 folders (Box 1)
  - Saginaw ?, 1871, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Morenci, 1873-1874, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor, 1875-1876, 8 folders (Box 1)
  - Fenton, 1876 (Box 1)
  - Port Huron, 1876, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Ypsilanti, 1881-1883, 15 folders (Box 1)
  - Ypsilanti, 1883-1884 and undated, 16 folders (Box 2)
  - Undated, 29 folders (Box 2)
  - Undated, 18 folders (Box 3)
  - Funeral sermon (Box 3)
  - Intemperance sermons (Box 3)
  - Thanksgiving Day sermon (Box 3)
- Essays
  - Essay "Charles Sumner," 1866 (Box 3)
  - History of Sunday School at Morenci (Box 3)